scanscout.com 2014-10-25

# Tremor Video, Inc. » Privacy Policy

**Opt Out of Interest-Based Advertising**

Tremor Video uses advertising cookies to improve the online experience of its users by trying to match the ads we serve to the possible preferences and interests of users.  By so doing, ads that Tremor Video serves may be more relevant and useful to you. You may always opt out of the cookies that Tremor Video uses to serve online interest-based advertising by clicking on the button above.  After you opt out, these cookies will no longer be associated with your browser. Ads may continue to be served based on information available in the Internet environment, such as the content of a web page, browser type, time of day and operating system.  If you have opted out of the cookies that Tremor Video uses and subsequently delete the “opt out” cookie from your browser, change your browser, or buy a new computer/device, you will need to opt out again of Tremor Video interest-based advertising, and you may always do so by clicking on the button above.

Last updated:  March 3, 2014

**Introduction**

This privacy policy describes the types of information that Tremor Video, Inc., we or Tremor Video, collects on our corporate website and through our video advertising services. It also describes how that information is used and the choices we offer to users, or you, about the collection and use of such information.

**PRIVACY POLICY FOR THE TREMOR VIDEO CORPORATE WEBSITE  **

[www.tremorvideo.com](http://www.tremorvideo.com/)  and [www.videohub.com](about:blank) are the corporate websites of Tremor Video, Inc. (“Tremor Video” or “we”). These websites (collectively, the “Tremor Video Site” or “Site”) provides users, usually current and prospective customers, partners, and job seekers, with information about our products and services, and gives users the opportunity to contact us for further information.

This privacy policy describes the types of information that Tremor Video collects on the Site and how that information is used. Tremor Video reserves the right to modify this privacy policy at any time by posting the changes on the Site. Your continued use of the Site constitutes your acceptance of the current posted privacy policy. If you have questions about this privacy policy, please email us at privacy@tremorvideo.com.

**What information does the Tremor Video Site collect?**

Personally identifiable information  
Personally identifiable information is information that identifies a user as a specific individual, such as a name, email address, mailing address, or phone number, or data that you provide that Tremor Video can reasonably link to other information that you provide in order to personally identify you.

The Tremor Video Site collects personally identifiable information about users only if a user voluntarily provides that information to the Site. Personally identifiable information is collected on the Tremor Video Site in various instances including, without limitation:

  * Information requests. A Site user, typically a publisher, advertiser, partner, or job seeker, submits an inquiry to Tremor Video through the “Contact Us” function on the Site, and provides his or her name, address, email address, and/or telephone number so that Tremor Video is able to respond.

  * Comment on news, blog, or other posting. A user posts a comment in the blog or news section of the Site, and submits his or her name and email address in connection with the posting.

  * Subscribe to email newsletter. To subscribe to the Tremor Video email newsletter, a user provides his or her name, email address, and other contact information. Each newsletter will provide the user with the option of unsubscribing from future newsletters.

  * Subscription feed. A user subscribes to the Site’s subscription function by providing his or her email address.

  * Access to Tremor Video’s web-based client interface. A current Tremor Video client accesses the client/customer-only areas of the Site by submitting his or her username and password.

  * Request for feedback. From time to time, the Tremor Video Site may ask users for voluntary feedback that will help us improve the Site. In connection with such feedback, a user may choose to provide optional name and contact information.

  * Promotions, sweepstakes, or contests. From time to time, Tremor Video may sponsor or co-sponsor promotions, sweepstakes or contests, in response to which a user may provide information, such as his or her name, email address, or other contact information, and/or to answer certain questions on an entry form.

**Non-personally identifiable information**

Non-personally identifiable information includes demographic information (such as age, gender, city, or state) and a user’s clickstream information. The Tremor Video Site collects information about users and stores it in log files. This information includes non-personally identifiable information that your browser automatically sends whenever you visit this Site, including information about your web request, your IP address, your browser type, browser language, date, and time of the request.

**How does Tremor Video use the information collected by the Tremor Video Site?**

_Personally identifiable information_  
Tremor Video uses the personally identifiable information you provide to respond to your inquiries and requests, and to keep accurate records concerning the services you are requesting through the Tremor Video Site.

_Non-personally identifiable information_  
Tremor Video generally uses non-personally identifiable information in aggregated form to help measure the Tremor Video Site’s performance and effectiveness, and to improve its usefulness.

**With whom does Tremor Video share the personally identifiable information collected on the Tremor Video Site?**

Tremor Video does not share the personally identifiable information that you provide to the Tremor Video Site with any third party, other than with its service providers that help Tremor Video provide the services that you request, such as delivery of our email newsletters, and to help Tremor Video manage information provided by job seekers for possible employment with us.

Tremor Video may transfer the information it collects on the Site to any successor-in-interest to Tremor Video (such as a company that acquires Tremor Video), or internally to one or more affiliates (such as a corporate subsidiary or parent).Tremor Video may also disclose personally identifiable information about a user if it determines that an applicable law, regulation or legal process requires it, or if Tremor Video determines that it needs to share such information to protect or enforce Tremor Video’s rights or the rights of another user.

**What else should I know about privacy?**

_Security_

Tremor Video maintains safeguards to protect the security, integrity and privacy of the personally identifiable information within our reasonable control.  However, no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. Therefore, while we strive to protect your information, please be advised that Tremor Video assumes no responsibility or liability for disclosure of your information due to errors in transmission, unauthorized third-party access, or other causes beyond Tremor Video’s reasonable control.

_Links to other websites_

Tremor Video does not control the data collection policies of any third party website linked to the Tremor Video Site. If you click on a link or an advertisement, the privacy policy of the website to which you link will govern the collection and use of your information by that website’s operators. Tremor Video assumes no responsibility or liability for the actions of such third parties with respect to their use of your information or otherwise.

_Collection of information from minors_

The Tremor Video Site is directed to, and intended for use by, adults only. We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of thirteen. If we become aware that we have inadvertently received personally identifiable information from a user under the age of thirteen, we will delete such information from our records.

**ACCEPTANCE OF PRIVACY POLICY FOR THE TREMOR VIDEO SITE**

When you use the Tremor Video Site, you are accepting the terms and conditions of this privacy policy, and Tremor Video will have the right to use your information as described in this privacy policy. If you do not agree to have your information used in any of the ways described in this privacy policy, you must discontinue use of the Tremor Video Site.

* * *

We collect information about your activities on certain websites to send you targeted ads. To opt out of our targeted advertisements [click here](http://www.tremorvideo.com/about-us/privacy).

**PRIVACY POLICY FOR THE TREMOR VIDEO SERVICES**

**What does Tremor Video do?**  
Tremor Video is an online video advertising technology company that offers advertisers, agencies, and other buyers (“advertisers”) opportunities to display their video ads on websites and applications across the Internet, including websites and applications made available through mobile devices, tablets, and connected TVs.

**How does Tremor Video deliver ads?**  
Video ads delivered by Tremor Video primarily appear immediately prior to or during a third-party publisher’s streaming video content.

Most of our advertisers’ video ads are delivered to third-party publishers by Tremor Video proprietary ad-serving technology.

**How are ads selected for delivery?**

Tremor Video’s customers are advertisers that engage us to display their video ads. Advertisers may specify where, when, and in what context they want their video ads to be displayed. These specifications are sometimes called targeting parameters.

Tremor Video uses its proprietary technology to select, target, and deliver ads according to the advertisers’ specifications. In order to optimize the delivery of a video ad, the technology collects and analyzes information provided by the web publisher, user’s browser, and advertiser, among other sources, which, in turn, is automatically recorded by the servers of Tremor Video. Examples of the types of information we may collect and store in the server logs are the following: browser type and language, operating system, Internet Protocol address (for example, to identify a user’s general location), page URL and referral URL, video player size, content (such as video title, description, category) , date and time of request, internet service provider (such as Verizon FiOS),  and advertising cookies.  When selecting, targeting and delivering ads, Tremor Video does not actively collect, and does not use or store personally identifiable information about a user.

The Tremor Video proprietary ad-serving technology may use cookies, web beacons, and other similar technologies in order to select, target, and measure the effectiveness of advertisements, including when determining what ads to present so that they may best relate to the possible preferences and interests of users based on information collected across multiple websites that they visit. We call this practice of collecting data about a user’s online activities in order to deliver advertising targeted to a user’s likely interests “interest-based advertising.”

A “cookie” is generally a small text file that is sent to a user’s computer. Cookies are commonly assigned by online services, such as websites or ad technologies, to recognize a computer that they have encountered before. A cookie is associated with a specific site domain, a specific computer, and a specific Internet browser program.

Our advertising cookies operate anonymously: we never use them to gather the user’s name, street address, e-mail address, or telephone number(s).

A “web beacon” is a small piece of code placed on web pages that can be used, among other things, to count the users who visit the web page, or to deliver a cookie to the browser of a user viewing that page.

You can decline Tremor Video’s use of advertising cookies for interest-based advertising by clicking on the “Click to Opt Out” button at the top of this page.

Should you wish, you can set most modern browsers to reject cookies, and remove cookies that have already been placed. You can find out how to do so and otherwise manage cookies at [All About Cookies](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookies/).

You may also manage cookies from many companies at the [Digital Advertising Alliance Consumer Opt Out Page for the Self-Regulatory Program for Online Behavioral Advertising](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/).

**How does Tremor Video deliver ads to mobile applications?**

In the case of advertisements selected, targeted, and delivered to mobile applications, the ad-serving technology may collect information provided by the user’s mobile device, including the hardware’s unique device ID. Tremor Video changes the unique device ID into an anonymous ID, which we use to deliver advertisements to your mobile device.  In addition, Tremor Video may collect certain unique mobile operating system IDs, such as Apple’s Identifier for Advertising ID (IDFA), or Google’s Android ID and its Android Advertising ID, to select, target, and deliver advertisements because users are provided the opportunity to reset these identifiers or opt out of interest-based advertisements through the applicable settings features of their mobile devices. These opportunities are subject to the offerings made available by the third-party operating system providers and subject to their privacy policies, and not any offerings by or the privacy policy of Tremor Video.  Other examples of information we may collect to select, target and deliver advertisements may be the type of the mobile device and the location of a mobile device if a user enables collection of precise location data through the available features on that mobile device.

**How do we use third-party service providers?**

Tremor Video and its advertisers may also use third-party ad service providers to help deliver advertisements. These ad service providers use cookies, web beacons, or other technologies to select, target, deliver, and measure the effectiveness of advertisements, including when determining what ads to present so that they may best relate to the possible preferences and interests of users. Tremor Video may use data that ad service providers collect in the delivery of interest-based advertisements. This data is non-personally identifiable information and is used to deliver advertisements that may be more relevant to a user.

Tremor Video may share non-personally identifiable information about users gathered by means of cookies, web beacons, or other technologies, including anonymous identifiers used in connection with mobile applications, with certain ad service providers so that they can help Tremor Video deliver more relevant advertisements. The use of cookies, web beacons, or other technologies by other ad service providers is subject to their respective privacy policies, not the privacy policy of Tremor Video. You can find out more about ad service providers and the choices you have about these technologies by clicking on the links at the bottom of this privacy policy. Similarly, the publishers to which we deliver an ad are subject to their own privacy policies and not the privacy policy of Tremor Video.

You may view a list of third-party service providers, along with links to their websites, at the bottom of this page.

**Is information transferred to Tremor Video successors and affiliates?**

Tremor Video may transfer the information it collects in connection with its business to any successor-in-interest to Tremor Video (such as a company that acquires Tremor Video), or internally to one or more affiliates (such as a corporate subsidiary or parent). Tremor Video may also disclose information if it determines that an applicable law, regulation, or legal process requires it, or if Tremor Video determines that it needs to share such information to protect or enforce Tremor Video’s rights or the rights of another user.

**ABOUT THIS PRIVACY POLICY**

Tremor Video reserves the right to modify this privacy policy at any time. If you have questions or concerns about this privacy policy, please email us at privacy@tremorvideo.com or write to us at Tremor Video, Inc., Attention: Privacy, 53 West 23rd Street, New York, NY 10010.

**US Self-regulatory program for online behavioral advertising**

Tremor Video follows the Digital Advertising Alliance industry privacy standards for online behavioral advertising. To learn more about the program and its principles, [visit the Digital Advertising Alliance](http://www.aboutads.info/).

US-EU Safe Harbor Framework

Tremor Video is registered with the U.S. Department of Commerce’s US-EU Safe Harbor program, and we adhere to the Safe Harbor Framework regarding the collection, use, and retention of data received from the European Union (EU). In the event there is a written complaint submitted to Tremor Video regarding the transfer of personal data from the EU that Tremor Video is unable to resolve, we will cooperate with the appropriate regulatory authorities, including the EU Data Protection Authorities. [Visit the US-EU Safe Harbor program](http://export.gov/safeharbor/) to learn more.

**Third-party ad service providers**

The following third-party ad service providers may use cookies, web beacons, or other technologies in connection with advertisements delivered by Tremor Video. Click on the links below to find out more about their practices, and the choices they provide to you:
